JED BRENNEN

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

CONTACT INFO

(+44) 07446914778

jedbrennen@gmail.com

https://jedbrennen.me

London

EXPERTISE

FRONT END	BACK END
JS/Typescript	Python
React	Node
Redux	Java
ChartJS	SQL
Angular	NoSQL
SCSS/SASS	REST
BEM	GraphQL
Jest Enzyme	CI/CD
Mocha	GitHub
Cypress	AWS
Storybook	Firebase
Flutter	Docker

EDUCATION

2014-2018

BSc Computer Science w/ Industrial Year 1st Class Honours University of Reading

PROFILE OVERVIEW

Full stack developer with a 1st class degree in Computer Science. bringing proven practical experience from nearly four years working across the stack, writing high quality, testable code, using technologies such as JS/React, Python and SQL.

JOB EXPERIENCE

AIG INTERNATIONAL

Front End Developer / December 2020 - Present

London, UK **?**

Front end developer across multiple teams, with some back-end involvement as well.

- Stack included Typescript, React, Redux, ChartJS, Python, Django and GraphQL.
- Collaborated with other developers and UI/UX to build internal search, data visualisation and annotation tools for various desks to improve efficiency in managing their portfolios. Features included charts (ChartJS), maps (ArcGIS), data tables and document readers with annotation capabilities.
- After 9 months, I was entrusted with spearheading a new trends chart feature as the only front-end developer in a different team. Following completion of the feature I worked on building out a new module for the product, built on a GraphQL API, a first for the platform.
- Frequently contributed to a common UI library. Pushing for quality and consistency across components and in constant communication with the other developers and designers to ensure new components are fit for purpose across teams.
- Regularly requested more full-stack responsibilities, taking on some Python/Django work alongside my frontend tasks. This involved building dataset makers, models and migrations to transform data from new sources.
- Helped with interviewing new front end developers, both contractors and permanent. Including reviewing and improving the interview process.

JOB EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

SAGE PEOPLE

Software Engineer / May 2020 – December 2020 Graduate Software Engineer / July 2018 – May 2020

Reading, UK 9

Full stack developer building an HR platform using Salesforce and Angular, later transitioning to mobile development.

- Initially working on an HR platform built with Angular and Redux on the front end, using Salesforce and Apex as the backend. I collaborated with design and product owners to build new features with highly testable code, regularly participating in code reviews and agile methodologies to ensure a quality outcome.
- Attended Angular Connect and used learnings from the conference to overhaul the product's Angular
 test suite, saving minutes of test execution time in most modules whilst preserving coverage. I
 presented my work to the department to improve department-wide understanding of writing more
 efficient tests.
- Involved in a hackathon team building a faster, more developer and user friendly mobile application for the platform with Flutter. Following presentation to the senior leadership team, development of the app was formally added to the product roadmap and my team transitioned to full time mobile development.
- Built a real-time sprint retrospective board with another developer from my team, to replace the sticky notes we had been using. Initially built with Angular and Firebase, I later rewrote the app in React having taken an interest in the framework. The rebuild focused on improving usability and multi-team capabilities, allowing the entire department to use the tool.

URBAN SCIENCE INTERNATIONAL

Analyst (Part-time) / August 2017 – March 2018 Intern / June 2016 – August 2017

Reading, UK **?**

Joining as an intern for my industrial placement, I processed raw data from various sources using SQL, SQl Server and Excel and deployed the result to the live systems. This involved performing QA on the data and fixing any errors from processing, fixing and improving stored procedures used in processing and communicating with clients regarding their live environments. I was also responsible for querying the data to produce various reports for certain clients. For a 3-month period, I worked remotely with a team in Germany to develop a new feature for one of the products using Java and JSP. In addition, throughout my time at the company, I learned C# to help maintain and improve my team's internal data and task tracking tool. Following my internship, I continued as an Analyst for 7 months, part-time, whilst finishing my final year of university.

ADDITIONAL INTERESTS AND EXPERIENCE

Before university, I undertook an expedition traveling across Africa, from Namibia to Tanzania. This was the culmination of a 2-year project involving planning the expedition and fundraising, both within a team and independently. During the expedition, I led the team on multiple occasions, including part of a trek up Mount Kilimanjaro and during a volunteering project building housing for a village in Zambia.

Outside of development I enjoy keeping active, playing American Football a couple of times a week with a team based in London and going to the gym to support this. I also enjoy learning about music production/performance as a hobby, regularly DJing for fun with friends.